Guide to the Records of the Women's Bureau of the U.S. Department of Labor, Pt.2, Series A on Microfilm, 1918-1965
Records of the Women's Bureau of the U.S. Department of Labor, Pt.2, Series A on Microfilm.
- Geographical Files (continued) (Reel 7)
  - Ravenna, OH Defense Area, 1942; 14 (Reel 7)
    March 1942. Includes Facilities for Transportation, Eating, Recreation, Housing, and Child Care; List of Persons Interviewed; Agency Coordinating Activities for Defense; Sanitary Facilities; Education Facilities; and Booklet relating to the Ravenna Ordnance Plant. 100 frames.
  - Dayton-Springfield, OH., 1944-1945; 15 (Reel 7)
    Includes Comments by Workers along with Facts regarding Their Age, Marital Status, Number of Children and Wages; Reasons Given by Women for Stopping Work; Child Care Problems; Postwar Employment Expectations of Women Workers in Dayton; and Proceedings of the Ohio Institute on Postwar Employment of Women. 109 frames.
  - Sidney, OH., 1942; 16 (Reel 7)
    August 21, 1942. Includes War Plants in Sidney Employing Women Workers; Labor Supply; and the National Defense Training Program. 8 frames.
  - Minority Report by A. Plotkin, Co-Chairman of the Subcommittee on Methods of Integrating Safety into Production and Industrial Organizations., 1950; 17 (Reel 7)
    May 2, 1950. 8 frames.
  - Illinois: Illinois Governor's Conference on Industrial Safety. Report of the Committee on Education., 1950; 18 (Reel 7)
    May 1-2, 1950. 38 frames.
  - Illinois Governor's Conference on Industrial Safety. Report of the Committee on Accident Records, Analysis and Uses., 1950; 19 (Reel 7)
    May 1-2, 1950. 27 frames.
  - Illinois Governor's Conference on Industrial Safety. Report of the Committee on Health and Hygiene., 1950; 20 (Reel 7)
    May 1-2, 1950. 73 frames.
  - Crab Orchard Lake Area, Illinois, 1944; 21 (Reel 7)
    July 26, 1944. Includes Population; Recreational Facilities; Report on the Crab Orchard Defense Area, Illinois Ordnance Works; Defense Activities; Housing, Transportation, Education, Sanitation, and Health Facilities; and Report on Industrial Labor in Southern Illinois. 154 frames.
- Geographical Files (continued) (Reel 8)
  - East Alton, IL., 1 (Reel 8)
    n.d. Includes Population; Industrial Pattern of the Area; Labor Supply; Transportation; Housing; Recreational Facilities; and Personal Interviews with Women Woerkers at the Western Cartridge Company regarding Contract Bonuses, Wage Rates, Working Hours, Food Facilities, Rest Periods, Rotation of Shifts, Age, Marital Status, Child Care, Absenteeism, Reasons for Leaving Jobs at Plant, Comments on Unions in the Plant and List of Persons Interviewed. 42 frames.
  - Joliet, IL Defense Area., 2 (Reel 8)
    n.d. Includes Towns Within the Area; War Plants; Transportation Facilities; Housing; Child Care; Health and Educational Facilities; Recreation Facilities; and List of Persons Interviewed. 65 frames.
  - Rockford, IL., 1942; 3 (Reel 8)
    September 9, 1942. Includes National Defense Training Programs for Women. 19 frames.
  - Rock Island-Moline-Davenport Defense Area., 4 (Reel 8)
    n.d. Includes Economic Structure of the Area; Transportation Facilities; Housing; Eating Facilities; Child Care; Health and Educational Facilities; Recreational Facilities; Report of the Director, Homes Registration Offices; Directory of Manufacturers and Wholesalers in Rock Island, IL; and Pamphlet from the Rock Island, IL Chamber of Commerce. 89 frames.
  - Savanna, IL Ordnance Depot, 1942; 5 (Reel 8)
    February 13, 1942. Includes Transportation Facilities; Housing; Child Care; Health and Recreational Facilities. 25 frames.
  - Postwar Planning Study with Women's Organizations in Indiana., 1945; 6 (Reel 8)
    Includes Employment of Negroes in Indiana; Trend of Non-White Employment in Indiana; Figures on the Employment of Women in Indiana; List of Indiana Industrial Plants and Plant Sites to Be Disposed of by the Defense Plant Corporation; Employment Situation in Evansville, Gary, Hammond, Fort Wayne, South Bend, and Indianapolis; Employment Status of Women in Indiana; Major Occupations of Women in Indiana; Marital Status of Women in the Work Force in Indiana; Conference on War and Postwar Adjustments for Women Workers; Meeting of Representatives of Indiana Women's Interest Organizations; Estimated Impact of Demobilization in Indiana; Indiana State Labor Laws for Women; and the Regional Conference on Women in Post War Planning. 361 frames.
  - Burns City, IN., 7 (Reel 8)
    n.d. Includes Housing, Eating, and Recreational Facilities; Characteristics of the Area; Transportation Facilities; and Health Facilities. 15 frames.
  - Charlestown, IN., 1943; 8 (Reel 8)
    December 13, 1943. Includes Sanitary facilities; Transportation Facilities; Housing; Child Care; Health Facilities; Recreational Facilities; Educational Facilities; and Labor Supply. 31 frames.
  - Jeffersonville-Charlestown-New Albany, IN Defense Area., 1942; 9 (Reel 8)
    January 1942. Includes US Quartermaster's Depot in Jeffersonville and the Indiana Ordnance Plant, the Dupont Powder Plant, and the Hoosier Ordnance Plant in Jeffersonville; Labor Supply; Transportation Facilities; Methods of Recruiting and Hiring; Requirements for Women Office Workers; Personnel Policies; National Defense Training Courses; Housing; Recreational Facilities; Employment of Negroes; Child Care; and List of Industries in Jeffersonville. 61 frames.
- Geographical Files (continued) (Reel 9)
  - Indianapolis, IN., 1943; 1 (Reel 9)
    February 1943. Includes Demand for Women Workers; Transportation Facilities; Housing; Training of Women for War Industries; Child Care; Recreational Facilities; and Labor Organizations in the Area. 41 frames.
  - South Bend-Kingsbury, IN Defense Area, 1943; 2 (Reel 9)
    January 13, 1943. Includes Kingsbury Ordnance Plant; Recreational Facilities; Housing; Child Care; Transportation Facilities; Health Facilities; Methods of Recruiting and Hiring; Labor Supply; Work Hours; Vocational Training Programs; and Personnel Policies. 79 frames.
  - Kenosha, WI., 3 (Reel 9)
    n.d. Includes General Comments by Workers; Reason of Women for Stopping Work; and Child Care Problems in Kenosha. 19 frames.
  - Milwaukee, WI., 1943; 4 (Reel 9)
    February-March 1943. Includes War Plants in the Milwaukee Area; Labor Supply; Working Conditions for Women; Vocational Training Programs; Transportation Facilities; Housing; Child Care; Recreational Facilities; Employment of Negroes; Labor Organizations in the Area; Industrial Accidents; and Absenteeism. 15 frames.
  - Burlington, IA., 1942; 5 (Reel 9)
    February 1942. Includes Economic Structure of the Area; Transportation Facilities; Housing; Child Care; Health Facilities; Educational and Recreational Facilities; Labor Supply; Iowa Ordnance Plant; Industrial Accidents; Job Description of Women's Work at the Iowa Ordnance Plant; Working Conditions for Women; Personnel Policies Pertaining to Women; Employment Situation in Burlington; Prevailing Wage Scale in Burlington; List of Leading Industrial Plants in Burlington; and the Group Insurance Plan for the Iowa Ordnance Division Employees of Day & Zimmerman, Inc.. 148 frames.
  - Cedar Rapids, IA., 1943; 6 (Reel 9)
    November 1943. Includes Child Care and Housing. 3 frames.
  - Keokuk, IA., 1945; 7 (Reel 9)
    September 1, 1945. Includes War Plants in the Area. 2 frames.
  - Wichita, KS., 1944; 8 (Reel 9)
    Includes Comments by WOrkers regarding Jobs and Wages and Reasons Given by Women for Stopping Work. 17 frames.
  - Hutchinson KS., 1943; 9 (Reel 9)
    February 1943. Includes Economic Characteristics of the Area; Housing; and Recreational Facilities. 5 frames.
  - Parsons, KS., 1942; 10 (Reel 9)
    November 25, 1942. Includes Kansas Ordnance Plant; Economic Characteristics of the Area; Housing; Recreational Facilities; Child Care; Labor Market Development Report for Parsons; Labor Supply; Sanitation and Health Facilities. 48 frames.
  - Wichita, KS., 1944; 11 (Reel 9)
    April 11-14, 1944. Includes War Plants in the Area; Child Care; Hours of Work; Transportation Facilities; Housing; National War Labor Board Decisions Affecting Unions Working at Wichita War Plants; Industrial Pattern in Wichita; Labor Market; Recruitment Methods; Recreational Facilities; and National Defense Training Programs in Wichita. 109 frames.
  - Greater Kansas City Defense Area in Missouri and Kansas., 1941; 12 (Reel 9)
    December 4, 1941. Includes Industrial Patterns in Kansas City; Labor Supply; Transportation Facilities; Housing; National Defense Training Programs; Recreational Facilities; and Industrial Statistics for the Greater Kansas City Area. 24 frames.
  - St. Louis, MO., 13 (Reel 9)
    n.d. Includes recreational facilities; Housing; Health Facilities; Industrial Pattern of St. Louis; Labor Supply; Transportation Facilities; Child Care; List of Defense Plants in the St. Louis Area; Vocational Training Programs; List of Manufactureres in St. Louis Employing Women Workers; and Wages and Hours of Women Workers. 61 frames.
  - Sidney, NE., 14 (Reel 9)
    n.d. Includes Labor Supply; Housing; Recreational Facilities; Child Care; and the Farm Labor Situation. 6 frames.
  - Jacksonville, AR., 15 (Reel 9)
    n.d. Includes Economic Structure and Population Changes in the Area; Transportation Facilities; Housing; Child Care; Educational and Recreational Facilities; Health Facilites; the Arkansas State Trade School; National Defense Training; and the US Employment Service Activities Report for Arkansas. 57 frames.
  - Greater Little Rock, AR Defense Area, 16 (Reel 9)
    n.d. Includes Housing; List of Manufacturers in the Greater Little Rock Area; Population Data and Vital Statistics for Little Rock; Economic Structure of Little Rock; and Employment of Women in Greater Little Rock Area War Plants. 62 frames.
- Geographical Files (continued) (Reel 10)
  - Louisiana, 1943; 1 (Reel 10)
    July 1943. Includes Employment of Women in Louisiana. 7 frames.
  - Minden, Louisiana Defense Area, 1942; 2 (Reel 10)
    March 10, 1942. Includes Economic Structure and Population Changes in the Area; Transportation Facilities; Housing; Eating Facilities; Child Care; Health Facilities; Educational and Recreational Facilities; Louisiana Ordnance Plant General Safety Regulations; and Industrial Activities in Shreveport, Louisiana. 99 frames.
  - Oklahoma City, OK., 1943; 3 (Reel 10)
    April 1943. Includes Industrial Pattern of the Area; Labor Supply; Child Care; Housing; Recreational Facilities; and a List of Major War Plants in the Oklahoma City Area. 19 frames.
  - Tulsa, OK., 1943; 4 (Reel 10)
    April 1943. Includes Economic Characteristics of the Tulsa Area; Labor Market; Negro Problem in Tulsa; Recreational Facilities; Housing; Child Care; National Defense and Youth Training Programs; and Transportation Facilities. 32 frames.
  - Texarkana, TX., 1942; 5 (Reel 10)
    April 1942. Includes Defense Plants in the Texarkana Area; Economic Structure and Population Changes in the Area; Sanitary Facilities; Transportation Facilities; Housing; Eating Facilities; Child Care; Health and Educational Facilities; Recreational Facilities; List of Manufacturing Industries in Texarkana Area; and Bowie County Sanitary District Regulations. 93 frames.
  - Dallas, TX., 1941; 6 (Reel 10)
    December 1941. Includes Industrial Pattern of the Dallas Area; Labor Supply; National Defense Training Programs; Housing; Recreational Facilities; and Trasportation Facilities. 19 frames.
  - Fort Worth, TX., 7 (Reel 10)
    n.d. Includes Housing; Transportation Facilities; Child Care; Recreational Facilities; Industrial Pattern of Fort Worth; Labor Supply; and National Defense Training Programs. 15 frames.
  - Note Cards Listing Companies Employing Women in Kansas, Missouri, and Wyoming, 8 (Reel 10)
    n.d. Includes St. Louis, MO; Rock Springs and Cheyenne, WY; and Witchita and Kansas City, KS. 15 frames.
  - Colorado, 1943; 9 (Reel 10)
    May 1943. Includes Employment of Women in Colorado War Industries and the Colorado Labor Market. 5 frames.
  - Denver, CO., 10 (Reel 10)
    n.d. Includes Local Defense Industries; Labor Supply; Labor Recruitment; Vocational Training Programs; Housing; Recreational Facilities; Transportation Facilities. 9 frames.
  - Ogden, UT., 1943; 11 (Reel 10)
    April 1943. Includes Labor Needs; Transportation Facilities; Child Care; Vocational Training Programs; Ogden Defense Industries; Recreational Facilities. 4 frames.
  - Salt Lake City, UT., 1943; 12 (Reel 10)
    April 1943. Includes Employment of Women in Defense Industries; Transportation Facilities; Vocational Training Progams; Recreational Facilities; Child Care; Housing; and Labor Organizations in Salt Lake City. 31 frames.
  - Note Cards Listing Companies Employing Women Workers in Arizona, California, Illinois, Missouri, New York, Oregon, Texas, and Utah., 13 (Reel 10)
    n.d. Burbank, Emeryville, San Francisco, Los Angeles, Pasadena, and Oakland, CA; Sapulpa, OK; Tucson, Nogales, Douglas, Phoenix, Clifton, Benson, Safford, Flagstaff, Cottonwood, Wickenburg, Buckeye, Goodyear, Kingman, Yuma, Ajo, Casa Grande, Mesa, San Carlos, Tiger, Glendale, Safford, Winslow, Chandler, Globe, Superior, Morristown, Holbrook, Davis Dam, Scottsdale, Tempe, and Coolidge, AZ; El Paso and San Antonio, TX; Portland, OR; New York City, NY; Denver, CO; St. Louis, MO; Chicago, IL; and Salt Lake City, UT. 65 frames.
  - San Francisco-Oakland, California Area., 1945; 14 (Reel 10)
    December 20, 1945. Includes Postwar Employment Expectations of Women Employed in the San Francisco-Oakland Area; Comments of Workers in the San Francisco-Oakland Area with Facts regarding Their Age and Marital Status; Reasons of Women for Stopping Work; National Defense Training Programs; and Labor Supply. 108 frames.
  - San Diego, CA., 1943; 15 (Reel 10)
    November 7, 1943. Includes Community Factors Contributing to Turnover among Women in San Diego War Industries; Transportation Facilities; Housing; Child Care; Labor Supply; National Defense Training Programs; Recreational Facilities; and Labor Organizations in the San Diego Area. 109 frames.
  - Seattle-Tacoma, WA Area, 16 (Reel 10)
    n.d. Includes General Comment of Workers in the Area along with Facts regarding their Age and Marital Status and Reasons of Women for Stopping Work. 14 frames.